Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Sidney A. Olson Papers, 1957 RL.00737
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Sidney A. Olson papers
1957
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
RL.00737
9 Linear Feet
100 Items
Access Restrictions
Access to some portions of the J. Walter Thompson Company Archives is restricted.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Sidney A. Olson Papers were transferred to the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library from the J. Walter Thompson Company in 1987.
Biographical Note
Chronology
1908, April 30 Born, Salt Lake City, Utah
ca. 1925-1929 Attended the University of Utah
1934-1939 House Correspondent and City Editor, Washington Post
1939-1950 Senior Editor, Time, Life and Fortune magazines, Time, Inc.
1951-1956 Creator of the Ford Motor Company The American Road show Copy Supervisor, Kenyon and Eckhardt.
1956 Copy group head, J. Walter Thompson Company, New York office
1956-1973 Vice President, J. Walter Thompson Company, New York office
Collection Overview
The papers of Sidney A. Olson date to 1957. They consist of reports and artwork created during a trip to identify production locations in Asia and the Middle East for the Ford Motor Company television campaign, Proved and Approved Around the World. The reports describe highlights of the areas visited and include observations of local political and social conditions.
The Reports include descriptions of Phnom Penh and Angkor Wat, Cambodia; Rangoon, Burma; Bangkok, Thailand; Agra, Calcutta and Benares, India; Baghdad, Iraq; Istanbul, Turkey; and Paris, France. The Artwork includes production sketches of Rangoon and Bangkok only. Olson was accompanied by J. Walter Thompson Company writer Finley Hunt. The reports were written to Robert Maitland of the New York office of the J. Walter Thompson Company.
For related papers in the J. Walter Thompson Company Archives, see a reference archivist.
India -- Description and travel; Iraq -- Description and travel; Turkey -- Description and travel; Advertising media planning; Advertising agencies -- New York; Design drawings; Copy writers; J. Walter Thompson Company; Ford Motor Company
- Reports, 1957, May 15-June 12.
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes reports written by Sidney A. Olson during a trip to identify production locations for a Ford Motor Company campaign. Some reports are missing or incomplete.
  Arrangement note
  Arranged by report number.
  - Report No. 2 Phnom Penh, 1957, May 15 (Box 1)
  - Report No. 3 Angkor Wat, 1957, May[?] (incomplete) (Box 1)
  - Report No. 5 Rangoon, 1957, May 23 (Box 1)
  - Report No. 6 Rangoon, Calcutta, Benares, 1957, May 25 (Box 1)
  - Report No. 7 Benares, Agra, Calcutta, 1957, May 28 (Box 1)
  - Report No. 8 Baghdad, 1957, June 1 (Box 1)
  - Report No. 9 Istanbul, 1957, June 3 (Box 1)
  - Report No. 10 Istanbul, 1957, June 3 (Box 1)
  - Report No. 11 Paris, 1957, June 12 (Box 1)
- Artwork, 1957.
  Includes original production sketches made by Olson of various locations to which he traveled. There are also copies in various formats of the sketches.
  Arranged by format, then by sketch number with unnumbered sketches in alphabetical order at the end.
  - Original sketches on paper:, 11 folders
    - Rangoon 1, 1957, May 21 (Box 1)
    - Rangoon 2, 1957, May 21 (Box 1)
    - Rangoon 3, undated (Box 1)
    - Rangoon 4, undated (Box 1)
    - Rangoon 5, undated (Box 1)
    - Rangoon 6, undated (Box 1)
    - Rangoon 7, undated (Box 1)
    - Rangoon 8, undated (Box 1)
    - Bangkok, Royal Baron Procession, undated (Box 1)
    - Bangkok, Temple of the Dawn, 1957, May 19 (Box 1)
    - Swan boat, undated (Box 1)
  - Black crayon sketches on transparencies (use copies in form of photocopies):, 2 folders
    - Rangoon 1, 1957, May 21 (Box 1)
    - Rangoon 2, 1957, May 21 (Box 1)
    - Rangoon 3, undated (Box 1)
    - Rangoon 4, undated (Box 1)
    - Rangoon 5, undated (Box 1)
    - Rangoon 6, undated (Box 1)
    - Rangoon 7, undated (Box 1)
    - Rangoon 8, undated (Box 1)
    - Bangkok, Royal Baron Procession, undated (Box 1)
    - Bangkok, Temple of the Dawn, 1957, May 19 (Box 1)
    - Swan boat, undated(2 transparencies) (Box 1)
  - Phototransparencies (35 mm) of original artwork:, 1 folder
    - Rangoon 1, 1957, May 21 (Box 1)
    - Rangoon 2, 1957, May 21 (Box 1)
    - Rangoon 3, undated (Box 1)
    - Rangoon 4, undated (Box 1)
    - Rangoon 5, undated (Box 1)
    - Rangoon 6, undated (Box 1)
    - Rangoon 7, undated (Box 1)
    - Rangoon 8, undated (Box 1)
    - Bangkok, Royal Baron Procession, undated (Box 1)
    - Bangkok, Temple of the Dawn, 1957, May 19 (Box 1)
    - Swan boat, undated (Box 1)
  - Clipping, 1957. (Box 1)
    Front page of The Nation (Burma) with an announcement of the arrival in Rangoon of a team from the World Highways Expedition Corporation of America.